Dmitrijs Odinokijs



Engineer, Researcher, Developer

- ☐ Riga, LV
- □ +371 26708549
- □ dmitry.odinoky@gmail.com
- □ LinkedIn
- □ GitHub

Summary

MSc (Eng) focused on robotics, artificial intelligence, acoustics, and human perception. Researcher/engineer/developer with wide skillset and strong background in music/audio industry.

Specialization: Robotics, AI (deep learning), Data Science, Scientific Research, Software Prototyping & Testing, Music Production, Sound Engineering, Project Management, Education, Sound Design

Work Experience

Data Scientist / ML Engineer

ShipProjects | Riga, LV | 2024-08 - present

Data analysis, training and deployment of machine learning models, product research and development.

Research Engineer

Sonarworks | Riga, LV | 2018-08 - present

Participated in the internal prototyping, development and testing of such products as SoundID Reference, VoiceAl and SoundID™ Audio Personalization App.

Product Specialist, Customer Support

Yamaha Music Europe | 2012-09 - present

Work on part-time basis over 10 years, support product dealers by answering e-mail requests during weekends (7-10 requests/month).

Ableton Certified Trainer, Steinberg Certified Trainer, Music Producer

Dynamic Records | Riga, LV | 2008-01 - 2018-04

Became the only Ableton & Steinberg certified tutor in Baltics.

Lead Teacher, Project Manager in Sound & Music Production School

SIA Dinamic Records (soundschool.lv) | Riga, LV | 2009-01 - 2018-04

Led music production school and recording studio in Riga over 10 years.

Sound Production

Radio PIK | Riga, LV | 2007-10 - 2010-12

Worked as sound engineer at local radio station.

Education

Master of Engineering

Rigas Tehniskā universitāte (Riga Technical University) | 2020 - 2023-06

MEng, Robotics and Artificial Intelligence

Bachelor's Degree

Rigas Tehniskā universitāte (Riga Technical University) | 2017 - 2020-06

Bachelor's degree, Robotics and Artificial Intelligence

Qualifications

- Data Science
- Machine Learning
- Psychoacoustics
- Research and Development (R&D)
- Acoustics
- Sound Design
- CI/CD, git, automated test frameworks
- Python for backend development, feature prototyping, data processing and visualization
- Python ML frameworks (PyTorch, TensorFlow, scikit-learn, etc)
- C++
- C#
- MATLAB
- SQL
- Docker
- Linux

Languages

• English: Advanced

· Latvian: Advanced

Russian: Native

Certifications

- Ableton Certified Trainer
- Audio Signal Processing for Music Applications (Universitat Pompeu Fabra of Barcelona)